Hi, Elza here from Elza's bookshelf.
It's time for spring's last video before I take summer holidays,
So I was going to summarize the reading for Juni month.
It was a perfectly okay month, of which the top three is really top three.
I got a positive surprise.
I can tick off some things on my book challenges.
Over all very good months.
So that's why I think we start with, before I say hello then and explain a little how I think before the summer,
So I think we start by talking about the books I have read in June.
And of course I start with the one I liked at least and end with the one I like best.
And let's start with the one I liked at least, that was the world literature.
I went to India and read Visny's death by Manil Suri.
This sounds like a perfect book for me, because I like when it's a little magical realism.
It may be a touch of philosophy and such.
But it doesn't reach me.
I don't think this is good at all.
Just because this magical realism as a writer is trying to tackle, does not work.
It just gets ..
Strange instead.
There is no flow, there will be no good transitions.
The characters also feel ..
Not credible.
Because I get like this, wait, what happened now?
Why did he do that?
Why is he doing so there?
There is a lot that just hangs in the air.
I gave it the second.
It's a dust of book, so I can check it.
It's a world literature so I can tick it off.
But it is also such a book that I have included in the list of 10 books I will read in 2023.
That way it is nice that I can tick off this book.
Then I want to talk about months of random.
For those who have seen the reading logo
So every month I let in chance choose a book.
The book that was chosen for June I dnf-adoled.
I couldn't read it, I couldn't handle it.
So I took a new one in the Reading Log I choose a new one.
And then there were secrets at Sea View Cottage.
Yes, Emily Gunnis, Sea View Cottage.
I think I gave this one four, three and a half four like that.
And I am a hugety pike at Annie.
I understand
That she is a skilled writer, extremely good and I like her take on things.
Telling a whole life in this way is very fascinating.
Both me and no, but I'm glad I read Nobel Laureates, so I can say.
Then we have another pond of book, one that has been really dusty.
I think I've had this book since 2015-2016.
2015 it must have been.
Yes, 2015. I'm talking about Game of Thrones.
Here is the first book called Game of Thrones.
The series is called
A Song of Ice and Fire and the first book is called Game of Thrones.
And I've listened to it.
33 hours.
Over 33 hours was this one.
But God, what a good thing this was.
Unfortunately, I remember a lot from the TV series, because I have seen the TV series and I like the TV series very well, but I remember too much.
We are in Sweden.
It is the 19th century.
Mika lives in orphanages.
Things happen.
The two help and solve cases.
So, so good.
This one was just as good, but what I like about the book is that they are dark and that the author Johan trusts his readers.
Because it is still 9-12 years.
Trust their readers, let them take hard topics and can handle it.
He does it in a good way.
He writes it in a good way.
Strong four, of course.
And then we have one to dust off.
This is not just a dust off, but it bends in some.
This year was the year I would read Dona Tartt.
I own three Dona Tartt.
I posted a picture of the three books on Instagram and let you vote which Dona Tartt I would start with.
And the secret story won.
I'm super happy about it because I was most craving for this one.
We have to come along ... This is probably such a storytelling style.
That narrator is Richard.
I think he uses something.
Richard Pap may be a pronounced it.
He starts at a prestigious college.
Hangs with the elites there.
But everything is not right with these elites.
It's a lot like ... Yes.
Then you have to keep up with this gang anyway.
When they find some shenanigans.
It is dark.
It's so sick.
Well written.
Very thick.
Over 700 pages.
I swallow this one because it is incredibly character pity.
And the character is ... they may not be ... I don't like them.
I don't sympathize with them.
But I'm fascinated by them.
I want to know more.
Tartt has a way to explore man's innermost darkness in such a skillfully good way.
This was better than I thought it would be.
I had high expectations.
Be really nervous.
But wow.
I swallow this book.
It's very thick.
I wish I had it in another.
I wish I had the black cover.
This one is good looking.
I do not complain.
The black is a little better.
Mysterious.
I can't explain more than this one is so good.
It deserves the hype it has.
I'm glad I can check it now.
Now I can tick off the dust off.
And a Donna Tartt book that I said I would read.
A strong four.
Yes, a strong four.
My absolute favorite this year.
This month.
I have to say that it was a book that took me by surprise.
I was so surprised.
I did not have very high expectations.
I had no expectations at all.
I thought I would like to read it here, it's a dusted AV book, the classic.
I'm hungry and curious.
I had read another book by him and liked it very much.
I thought I have it at home.
Animal Farm by George Orwell.
Listen.
Listen what masterpiece this is.
This is the satire's satire.
It is incredibly smart, incredibly skillfully written and so damn spot on.
Okay, we're on a farm.
The animals do revolt against the humans.
This is about barley and pigs and horses that make revolt.
This is a satire.
This should make Narra how light power can corruption, how easily it can corrupt power.
How things, how it all started so well.
The animals should only support ourselves.
We know how it will be late to a dictator.
Very written, incredibly well written.
I am so impressed and it was much easier to understand and read than I thought it was.
I liked this much more than 1984, which I liked.
I liked in 1984, but this one is so damn good.
There is a new translation and that was the one I listened to.
So I didn't read it and I listened to it.
Wow.
I just say wow.
Now I want to know more about George Orwell.
Now I am very curious about him.
He is well sharp, incredibly good at putting words into things that I find difficult to describe myself.
Very happy that I can dust off this.
Now I want to know everything about George Orwell.
Who is he?
How did he think?
What happened?
That's how.
There we have the books that I have been able to read during Juni month, which you hear.
I am very peppy and recommend many of them.
Except for a book, Vishnus' death.
You know what?
Are you not interested?
Don't read it.
Do you think it sounds interesting?
Test it.
But I was not so impressed.
The rest of these books I have read this month have been absolutely fantastic and I recommend them, which you heard.
Then we got it clarified.
Now I'm going to take summer vacation.
I'll be back at the beginning of September sometime.
But I probably won't be completely gone.